Hey guys, welcome to a lost and final video of a session, network-based attacks.
So, there is not a lot of attacks in a network, but these are a few attacks we are commonly
worried about.
So, in this video, we will be going to discuss about the botnets.
So, botnets are the, it is a network of computers or devices, it is a group of computers,
so the group of computers that has been controlled by the attacker, so they can easily
be able to launch DOS or DDoS attack easily because there is a group of computers are there.
So, they can, they are controlling the attacker controlling these devices, so they can easily
launch any, any, any, any sort of attacks, ok.
So, under the control of malicious actor, so it will be on the control of a malicious
attacker, so they are in a full control over that machine, so they can easily do any
things in that device or elsewhere in a tool, so they can control all the machines and they
can launch the DOS or DDoS attacks, ok.
The compromised machines are known as the bots or zombies, because the devices looks like
some weird.
Then it will be, the performance will be a little bit slow sometime, the device performance.
So, if you are running a lot of service, so it will send the control to the attacker
machine, as well as if there is a control over the DDoS attacks, the attacker tells
that machine to do a DDoS attack, so that time you can feel some slowness in, in that
machine.
Yeah, this is a few things, and if you have a firewall, sorry, any sort of antivirus
softwares, so you can easily bypass this, because it is just C2C, command and control,
so if the IP was blocked, so now the attackers will not get anything into the machine,
ok.
So, the botnet detection, so we can easily detect the botnets by monitoring the initial
network traffic, so if you see any of the IP address with communicating with any, so
it was unnecessary, so you can easily tag, there is something happens and multiple network
connection with the same API, so already notified, there is a bulk DDoS, or DDoS attack
that can be launched from that machine, so you can see multiple network connection to
the same IP, some multiple services, so your system behavior was slow and your system
act like severe and slow, so now you can feel something happen to my computer, so you
can check there, whether there is a botnets or not by installing some antivirus, ok.
So, initial drag on process, sometimes some process will be keep on open and it will automatically
determine it in the end, so that will be the thing, ok, these are the few things, symptoms
for the botnets activity, so if you notify this kind of symptoms, so you can install some
IV software and you can scan that network, or you can see some what are the network connections
happening outside to the computer, and you can find out what the IP is about, ok, so let's
talk of this video and we will see you guys in our next session, thank you bye bye, I will
share the resource in the next section, thank you.